# 大块吃还过瘾
Big chunks are better
# 倒草莓 出锅了 真香
Pour in the strawberry and ready to serve Smells so good
# 吃完这鸡 豁然开朗
After having this chicken, suddenly enlightened
# 第一步我先把面包改了
first of all let me cut the bread first
# 改成骨牌块是吧
cut into domino pieces right？
# 根据人的需要你看
See，follow people’s need
# 进去到嘴里 实用 一口就下去了
Puts in your mouth suitable for one bite
# 这面包收拾完了 咱就搁这
Now it’s done Let’s just put the bread here
# 先切小料吧
Chop up the condiments first
# 很简单 胡萝卜
It’s simple carrots
# 我这是腌 蔬菜汁腌
I’m going to marinate it with veggie sauce
# 随便一切就行了
Just randomly chop it
# 提味又去腥是吧
Adds flavor and deodorize as well
# 芹菜 洋葱 胡萝卜
Chinese celery onion carrots
# 一个鸡腿 改个刀
A chicken leg recut it
# 深加工一下 剞刀口是吧
further process it deepen the cut
# 咱不用皮了
lets not use the skin
# 家里愿意用皮也可以
You can keep it if you want at home
# 鸡皮炸着吃也好吃
Fried chicken skin tastes good as well
# 炸完了一炒 炒香辣的
Fry with oil and then fry with spices
# 香辣鸡皮好吃极了
Spicy chicken skin tastes great
# 剞刀入味 然后切成鸡球 就是小鸡块
Make cuts to penetrate flavor, and then cut into bite size, small pieces of chicken
# 千万别打断了
Careful not to break it
# 那时候宴会就拿这个做宫保鸡花
Back then banquets would use this to make kung-pao chicken
# 那讲究
So fastidious
# 大的块儿 过瘾
Big chunks Super satisfying
# 咱今儿弄点儿横的 豪横
Let’s make quite a amount of it today
# 够了吧这点 够了
This is enough
# 这鸡咱就扔在蔬菜里面腌一下
Let’s cure the chicken in the vegetable
# 你看这蔬菜就这样腌完了
See the vegetables are done marinated
# 黄酒 盐
Rice wine salt
# 再来点胡椒粉提提鲜
And some pepper powder to add in some flavor
# 然后提一点糖就行
and add a tiny bit of sugar
# 腌它一会儿 腌它两三小时
cure it for a while about two or three hours
# 腌完之后你闻全是蔬菜味
after its been cured it smells like vegetable
# 蔬菜香味出来了
Veggie flavor has come out
# 把蔬菜捡了去 腌进味儿了
now get rid of the veggies the flavor is in
# 腌好了你知道它什么特点吗
you know how you can tell its done cured
# 你拿到手里都听话了 润了
its smooth when you hold it
# 调个青芥汁 好
mix some wasabi sauce
# （沙拉酱）还是不够
salad sauce is not enough
# 这回差不多 再来点
Now it’s enough add a little more
# 好 这回行了
Ok now we are good
# 青芥辣 好 不能太多了
Wasabi ok don’t put in too much
# 搁点柠檬汁 增加果香味
Sneeze in some lemon juice add in some fruit flavor
# 再来点蜂蜜 香气出来了
And some honey and here comes the smell
# 大家看看 这果香果还真浓 你闻闻
Here see, the fruit smell is so strong, smell it
# 先放一边 起锅坐油
Now put it aside, and heat the oil in the pot
# 拿蛋黄腌它（鸡肉）这个不用蛋清
marinate the chicken with egg yolk, we don’t need the egg white
# 再弄点淀粉 让它蘸点干淀粉
Put in some corn starch and dip it in
# 其实这菜做的很简单
It’s actually quite simple to make this dish
# 然后这些菜其实能做好多菜
And you can use these ingredients to make a lot of dishes
# 鱼香鸡球 宫保鸡球 沙律鸡球
Fish flavor chicken meatball Kung-pap chicken meatball, chicken meatball salad
# 全可以 黑椒的
All of them, black pepper flavor too
# 黑椒的咖喱的 方法多
Black pepper flavor, curry flavor, there are many ways
# 也可以炸完之后直接配着椒盐蘸着吃
You can also fry it and dip it in to pepper salt
# 它只能搁蛋黄 为什么不能搁蛋清啊
Why can’t you put in the egg white but only the egg yolk
# 为什么搁蛋黄啊梅子
Why only put in the yolk? Mei zi
# 一个是蛋黄香 蛋黄增香味
First yolk make the smell stronger
# 软度它会比蛋清口感要更好
And it’s softer which the texture is better than egg white
# 齐活 漂亮
All done, beautiful
# 师父油温好了吧   这回差不多了
Master the oil is warmed up, it’s ready this time
# 油温不能太低了
The temperature of the oil can be too low
# 太低的话油就吃面包里面去了
If it’s too low the bread would suck up all the oil
# 窝油了
Absorb too much oil
# 上颜色了啊
There comes the color
# 面包炸成金黄色
Fry the bread until it’s golden
# 控油了师父
Get it out of the oil Master
# 接着炸鸡 漂亮啊
Then fry the chicken, so pretty
# 码盘儿
Put in the dishes
# 让它紧凑点
Make it more tight to each other
# 这油温也差不多了师父
The oil temperature is ready Master
# 面包码好了啊 打底
The bread is done placing to be the priming
# 这油温起来了 雪花鸡球
The oil is warm now, snowflake chicken meatball
# 太有食欲了 看着有食欲吧
I’m having so much appetite, looks so good
# 它香啊
It smells good
# 师父这鸡得炸几遍啊
How many times do we need to fry the chicken Master?
# 这一般我都炸三遍
Usually I will fry it for three times
# 三遍就够了 炸酥脆了
Three times is enough to make it crispy and crunchy
# 现在已经熟了 定下型
Now it’s cooked, shape it
# 现在是沁炸 刚才是里边熟
We were deep frying it so the inside is cooked
# 熟完了 提高油温让它酥
Now it’s cooked, raise the temperature to make is crispy
# 这个菜说句实话这种方法炸
To be honest this way of frying this dish
# 切成丁 就这鸡花也行
Chopping into small bits and make it popcorn chicken could work as well
# 挂任何汁都好吃
use any sauce to go alone with it would taste good
# 你挂一宫保的汁 香极了
You can put Kung-pao sauce on it smell awesome
# 挂一酱爆汁都好吃
Or even soy sauce would taste good
# 因为大块吃还过瘾
It could really satisfy your craving because it’s such big chunks
# 这基本上快熟了 要浮起来了
this is almost ready, it’s about to float
# 颜色好看 里面也熟了
The color looks good and the inside is cooked as well
# 梅子 你可以来一块尝尝没问题
Mei zi you can have a piece to try if it’s good
# 这蔬菜的香味都出来了
The veggie flavor is coming out
# 这底口有蔬菜清香味
It has vegetable flavor in there
# 既酥又嫩
Crunchy and tender
# 小魏你尝尝 别说是师父偏心眼子
Xiao Wei you have a try, don’t say that Master has a favorite
# 怎么样 好吃 外焦里嫩
How is it? So good, crispy on the outside and tender in the inside
# 真特别好吃 真好吃诶
Truly really tasty, really good
# 这花椒面加点盐 对
Add in some salt in the pepper powder
# 炸好鸡颜色金黄 真漂亮
The fried chicken is golden, so pretty
# 这就行了
That’s it
# 这千万不能大火 不能太热
Definitely don’t use large fire, can’t make it too hot
# 这得关火 待会化了
Got to turn the fire off, it’s gonna melt soon
# 这个菜千万别大火
You should definitely not use large fire to make this dish
# 师父这锅热了
Master, the pan is hot
# 小火啊一定要小火
Small fire definitely small fire
# 锅热了把酱炒一下
If the pan is hot then cook the sauce
# 熟透了看那香气出来了
If it’s cooked the smell would be stronger
# （鸡肉）搁里没事 梅子搁里吧
Just put the chicken inside Mei zi it’s fine
# 得让它充分裹上边儿
Let all sides of it get covered
# 出锅 关火
Done and turn off the fire
# 你闻这香气 倒草莓
Do you smell the smell, pour in strawberries
# 出锅了 好了
Ready you serve, we’re done
# 真香 果香味也出来了
Smells delicious the fruit flavor is obvious too
# 这香死了 我天呐 太香了
Smell so good omg so good
# 我现在已经迫不及待想吃一口了
I can’t wait to have a bite now
# 梅子知道我们 其实是最早接宴会的
Mei zi knew we start out with making food for banquets at first
# 那时候全是大宴会
It was all huge banquets at the time
# 梅子跟着我 我们接完了我们创新
Mei zi followed me and we accept banquets and we innovate
# 看着有食欲 草莓上面搁几个
Just need to look to arouse the appetite, put some strawberries on the top
# 讲究不将就 做好了
Be precise don’t just put up with it, and now we’re done
# 等不及了啊 闻着就清香味
Can’t wait to try Smells so fresh
# 吃这个必须得吃块面包
You have to eat this along with the bread
# 就着个面包吃
Eat with the bread
# 我得来一块
I have to have a piece
# 我配着面包片
I’m going to eat along with bread crunches
# 觉得太好吃说不出话来了
So good that I can’t talk
# 这搭配 你知道吗
You know this combination
# 你听这声音 网友们
Listen to this sound friends
# 吃完这鸡 豁然开朗 闻着都香
So enlightened after having this chicken smells so good
# 真好 棒棒的
So good did a great job